if you recall when we talked about a
normal implication P implies Q we've
seen before that P implies Q is
logically equivalent to not Q implies
not P so I'm going to make use of that
logical equivalency when I try to go out
and prove things in particular my first
goal is going to be to try to prove an
implication that's what I'm trying to do
I'm trying to show prove an assumption
leads to a conclusion but what I'm going
to do is treat this as the other way
around I'm know that P implies Q is the
same thing as not Q implies not P that
is I'm instead going to go and try to
prove the Contra positive I'm going to
try to prove not Q implies not p and
that's the way I'm going to demonstrate
that P implies Q so let's see an
example in this theorem I'm saying if
the square is even then n itself is also
going to be even now I want to not
carefully this is different from the
theorem that we've seen in a previous
video this is not not saying if n is
even then n s is even it's the other way
around it's saying if n squar is even
then n is going to be even I'm going to
just try to use a direct proof and show
you why it might be challenging so my
assumption might be that N2 is even
which is going to be that N2 is going to
be twice some k for some K I'm not going
to write all my symbols down because
this is my plain around step I don't
have to be all that
precise all right and I want to say
something about n I've got this Square
here so maybe what I should be doing is
taking a square root of both sides that
might give me my n if I took the
positive square root for instance but
then what I have is it being like equal
to < tk2 * < TK K which doesn't really
look anything at all like being even so
assuming that my n squar was even and
taking square roots just didn't leave
anywhere it's got all this messy rot2
stuff floating around so proving it
directly seems a little bit challenging
so let's let's get rid of
that since proving this directly wasn't
all that useful let's try to prove it by
the contrapositive we're we're going to
do it the other way around with
negations so when I write it as proof by
contradiction by Contra positive rather
note what happens first of all the the N
squar is even and the N is even they
flip orders but they also get two knots
in that's what happens when I do Contra
positive so in other words I'm assuming
that n is not even and I'm trying to
deduce that n^2 is not even by the way
the Assumption n is not even is the same
thing as n is odd and the conclusion n
squ is not even is the same as the
conclusion n s is odd but I've actually
seen that particular proof before I've
seen a proof that n is odd implies N
squared is odd and so we can sort of
bring that one in and this is the proof
that we've seen before
indeed this claim n^2 even implies n is
even is the same claim it's logically
equivalent to n is odd implies n squ is
odd it's just that when it's written
this way in its contrapositive form it's
quite tractable and we were able to do
its proof almost directly it sort of
just fell out by our assumptions in a
way that just wasn't true when I tried
to directly prove the original so it's a
wonderful illustration of how a a proof
that's challenging and hard if you try
to go and prove its condra positive the
condra positive while logically
equivalent might be much easier to prove